

PETER NILS LINDBERG

peternlindberg at hotmail dot com | 917-715-6877 | Vancouver, WA in



SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

I am aspiring to transition from a 14 year IT (Systems / Engineering / Support) career into software development/engineering. I have over 8 years self-taught programming experience, and I have recently completed a Bachelors of Science in Computer Science degree, in 15 months, with a gpa of 3.9.

DEVELOPMENT TECHNOLOGIES

WPF • WCF • REST • Jquery • SQL • SilverLight • Node.js • Angular.js • Linux/POSIX • Android

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Pvthon • C/C++ • C# • JavaScript • Java • Perl • X86 Asm

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Time Student Jan 2014 to March 2015

Computer Science Bachelors degree program at Oregon State University. Project/code examples can be seen here: http://skaliak.github.io. Areas of study included:

- Programming languages, mainly Python and C with some C++, JavaScript, Java, and PHP
- **Data Structures**
- Algorithms (design and analysis)
- SQL and NoSQL databases
- Computer Architecture and Assembly Language
- Full-Stack Web Development (JQuery, AngularJS, Node.JS, PHP, CSS, HTML5)
- Software Engineering (e.g. Agile and Waterfall methodologies, Project Management, Team Leadership)
- Usability
- Cloud-Based PaaS systems, (e.g. Google App Engine)
- **Software Testing**
- Mobile App Development (Android)
- **REST Web Service APIs (both designing and consuming)**
- Networking
- Linux Programming with POSIX System Calls, in C and Python

Collegiate School - New York, NY

2004 to 2014

Oldest school in US with highly distinguished and selective community standing; grades K through 12.

NETWORK AND SYSTEMS ENGINEER

Technical expert and leadership role, carried robust technical oversight for all non-end-user devices, including Virtual Servers, VMware infrastructure, SAN/NAS, and LAN devices. Envisioned and capitalized on key opportunities for process improvements and cost savings. Acted as primary liaison to all vendors and solutions providers, forging partnerships to maximize products and services. Contributed advanced training to Faculty, Staff, and Students regarding diverse programs. including MS Office, SharePoint, and Adobe Creative Suite, Showcased mastery of software development to build, deploy, and support targeted solutions to diverse client needs.

- Captured \$100K in savings by implementing MS Lync as a phone system rather than a 'traditional' VoIP system; facilitated advanced features, including video calling, screen sharing, and dial-in conferencing.
- Advanced systems reliability to achieve "three 9s" level of service reliability and uptime.
- Architected software solution for importing teacher schedules into Exchange using C#, WPF, T-SQL, and SSIS; provided transparent process for end-users and enabled mobile access.
- Radically improved incident response time by delivering web-based ticketing system for help desk and building maintenance problem reporting, asset tracking, and parts inventory management.

PETER NILS LINDBERG

peternlindberg at hotmail dot com | 917-715-6877 | Vancouver, WA in

Collegiate School, cont'd...

- Led server virtualization, saving \$60K annually by implementing VMware ESX to expand bandwidth; the solution leveraged Essentials Plus pack on 3 hosts connected to enterprise-level EMC SAN.
- Attained \$40K in savings by replacing Cisco switches with HP switches.
- Deployed a SharePoint Enterprise server accessible by all school users; championed SharePoint for cloud storage and collaboration technologies and initiated migration of key paper-based procedures to online forms.
- Generated \$10K in annual savings by building a custom SQL database and developing software tools for managing ID
 photos and synchronizing with the user directory.

Howard County Public School System – Howard County, MD School district that manages public schools of Howard County, MD.

2003 to 2004

TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Provided technical support and oversight for up to 10 schools with approximately 1,000 computers. Ensured successful installation, administration, trouble-shooting, and repair for Apple Macintosh and Windows workstations and servers. Scope of technical oversight included setup and administration of OS X Server and Windows 2000 Server, as well as setup, configuration, software upgrades, and troubleshooting for 3COM managed switches and associated networks.

- Drastically reduced time required for setting up new computers from1 week to just 1 day by masterminding new OS X imaging techniques during deployment of ~600 eMacs over summer of 2003.
- Spearheaded introduction of numerous OS X lab administration techniques, such as Apple Remote Desktop, SSH, SCP, Mac Manager, and shell scripts.
- Led implementation of Symantec Ghost PC imaging software.
- Sole member of team to attain Apple Certification.

Friends School of Baltimore - Baltimore, MD

1999 to 2003

Private school in Baltimore that accepts students grade K through 12.

TEACHER & IT SUPPORT

Multi-faceted role, balancing technical support responsibilities while serving as the teacher of the upper school Animation class and Computer Graphics class. Ensured high-level execution of all help desk and training services for approximately 400 students and 50 faculty members. Entrusted with deploying and maintaining all Macintosh computers, as well as executing all hardware and software installations and upgrades on PCs and Macs.

- Achieved rapid promotion from part-time to fulltime role; gained increasing responsibilities based on exceptional performance.
- Deployed, configured, and maintained Win2k Advanced Server for streaming media and central audio/video file storage.
- Steered efforts to research and procure new hardware and software products.
- Designed and deployed key sections of school web page.

EDUCATION

BA in Art, Digital Imaging & Animation – University of Maryland 1998
BS in Computer Science – Oregon State University 2015, gpa 3.9

References available upon request